Vishal Tien

LinkedIn | GitHub | Email

SUMMARY

Passionate Machine Learning Engineer with 2 years of experience in ML spanning both research and industry, specializing in natural language processing. Domain expertise in pharma / healthcare and looking to grow my skills in the tech industry

Technologies: PyTorch, HuggingFace, Scikit-learn, AWS, Flask, React, Spark, NoSQL, Neo4j, Docker

Programming Languages: Python, C++, R, MATLAB, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Roivant Sciences, New York, NY

July 2021 - Present

Tech Rotational Analyst

- Sumitovant, AI for Knowledge Discovery Team NLP Scientist
 - Developing an NLP tool that combines rule-based pattern matching and a fine-tuned T5 deep learning language model to extract clinically relevant signals from large-scale biomedical corpora / social media, such as adverse drug events
- Sumitovant, Digital Innovator
 - Led the design and development of an ML product that analyzes Sumitovant's corporate reputation using information extracted from the web, enabling recommendation of marketing actions to the VP of Communications in a Flask application
 - Built and deployed NLP deep learning models (i.e BART) using HuggingFace and AWS SageMaker for topic modeling and document classification trained with zero-shot learning approaches and human-in-the-loop techniques, enabling automation in a data scarce environment
 - Integrated ElasticSearch into backend to increase speed of information retrieval and developed an interactive d3.js frontend visualization for React application that streamlines manual processes in drug discovery
- Sumitovant, AI for Knowledge Discovery Team Knowledge Graph / NLP Scientist
 - Built a biomedical knowledge graph (1M+ nodes and 4M+ edges) using Python and Turtle from disparate data sources to enable previously unanswerable drug discovery questions to be addressed
 - Implemented graph-based algorithms / GNNs to uncover insights from knowledge graph, such as disease-disease similarity
 - Trained a question answering information retrieval system by implementing an English to SPARQL (graph query language) deep learning generative language model, enabling the creation of a natural language interface that allows non-technical users to benefit form knowledge base, drastically increasing the impact it can have

Tsui Lab at Children's Hospital of Philadelphia, Philadelphia, PA

Dec. 2020 - July 2021

AI Researcher

 Constructed a CNN-LSTM model in PyTorch that predicted presence of life-threatening cardiac condition from clinical patient data, ultimately improving performance of current state of the art hospital solution by 77%

Merck & Co., Inc., Branchburg, NJ

Jun. 2020 - Aug. 2020

Data Science Intern – IT Emerging Talent Program

- Built machine learning classification model with > 99% accuracy in Python to uncover relationships between large structured / unstructured datasets without data dictionaries, improving recall of previously best performing model by ~50%
- Developed API wrapper written in R to allow data scientists to interact with a core product's API through easy-to-use functions

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA

August 2016 - May 2021

BSE in Bioengineering | Minors: Mathematics and Engineering Entrepreneurship (May 2020) | GPA: 3.8/4.0 MSE in Systems Engineering | Concentration in Data Science (May 2021) | GPA: 3.94/4.0

Awards: Senior Design Award, Rothberg Catalyzer Award, Publication, BMES Student Design and Research Award, Dean's List

PROJECTS

An Evaluation of Abstractive and Extractive Deep Learning NLP Text Summarization Techniques

- Final project for Principles of Deep Learning graduate course required contributing to the deep learning research field Deep Learning Chatbot with Deployment to Flask App
- · Created chatbot using neural network and NLP with task-oriented capabilities and interactive Flask front-end **Implementing Neural Network From Scratch**
- Constructed neural network from scratch using pure python and numpy and compared performance to PyTorch network Predicting Inpatient Length of Stay at Hospitals (TowardsDataScience Blog Post)
- Utilized Python on > 2 million rows of patient data to uncover clinically relevant insights and predict patient length of stay **NYC Restaurant Finder**
 - Developed full-stack React / Node is web application (demo) providing advanced restaurant search capabilities